Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number seven.
And this exercise, we are going to find the time complexity of this algorithm, so this algorithm is
containing two nested loops.
The The Outer Loop, the four and the inner loop is four, but it prints that system that are the print
app.
I am printing the values of IMJ.
Please post the video and think about this exercise.
Solve it on your own on paper.
OK.
I think you you solved it.
And let's try to solve this excessive exercise.
So.
We are dealing with and this course or the aim of this course is to learn you how to think logically
and how to think in algorithmic way and how the algorithms and the complexity works.
These exercises are very important for any interview.
And even in your subjects or even in your university, I need from you to to solve by your own these
exercises because they are very important.
We start.
We have a for loop here.
It starts from I equal to one and ends at eye equal less than or equal to an OK.
And that type of increment is a plus plus.
So these conditions are very important to understand and to determine the type and the time complexity
for this for a loop and every four.
So this for loop is being executed and times.
OK.
And minus one plus one is Anna plus one, this executed Anna plus one times.
But we have and we we we are interested in just getting the highest order of that equation.
Moving inside and.
This loop, this envelope.
Talking about this inner loop is being executed.
End times.
So it starts from one, though.
And and this is executed.
And times now this.
Lube contains a system that allowed the printer statement, and it is a constant, but we need to determine
the complexity of this loop.
It start from Jay equal to one.
Please pay attention, guys with me.
I reject sort of Jay equal to one and Jay less than an.
And Jay, that the incremental way of Jay is Jay Times two, we have solved in exercise number five,
this type of loop.
This type of complexity, but I will repeat.
Think about and I will take an as an example and put it as a.
OK, but let me first say that this would result in.
And of one.
And this.
Oh, of an OK.
So am equal to eight.
Let me show you at the first iteration.
I.
Jay and.
And.
And is constant at equal to it.
And we are not interested in since it is it will be executed eight times.
We are interested in J.
So every time is increased, J is executed.
How many times J starts from one?
OK, so the first iteration I was took, I equal to one.
And solve about it because we are not interested in I.
And since it's equal to one, I loop through Jay and start executing Jay.
So all these terms are equal to one, and Jay will be different.
I, j equal to one.
J.
Less than eight.
Yes, go and execute this statement, so the result?
Is executing system that out to print the state.
I sorry, Jay, is increased by one.
No, because J equals J Times do so, J is increased by the product, not by the plus plus.
So J the old, the new J is equal to that old J, which is one times two.
So the new J is equal now to two.
OK.
And is is it because it's constant and the result is executing the US system that out the print?
Now going to Jay Equal to one.
No, it is equal increased by Jay, the all the Jay is to here times two is equal to four.
So four is Jay starting from Jay equal to one.
And Jay, we see that condition.
Jay is four and and is equal to eight.
So four is less than eight.
Yes, go and execute the statement system that are that print again.
Jay is increased by times two, so four times two is equal to eight.
Jay is equal to eight now.
Jay less than.
No, it is equal to end.
So Jay is not less than.
And so it is stopping here that loop.
It will stop here and go up for AI and start AI again because it is AI is increased by + +.
Remember when increasing AI + +.
So this the slope will go all through all elements from one to N.
But this loop, the inner loop, is not going through all the elements from one and the end because
we have the elements from one to N is one order one two three four, five, six, seven and eight.
Look at this table J is moving from one.
Two, two, two, four and the stops because eight is not reached, so we have three elements from eight,
from eight numbers, we have chosen three numbers.
This will remember us with log eight numbers is equal to three.
Go and choose from these eight numbers.
Three.
This one result and a formula log eight equal to three.
Therefore, we are choosing from this encompass the log of them.
Therefore, the complexity of this inner loop is all of log, and because if we give eight numbers,
we are choosing three of them.
OK.
Therefore, we are executing this statement by one famous log and times.
And so.
Here and times and assorted log and times one.
Therefore, this result in and log.
So if we take an example of eight, we have executing AI from one to eight, we are executing AI eight
times.
And Log eight is three times and times one.
So this one result log eight, sorry, log eight is equal to three.
So eight times three times one.
OK, if we go and put this.
This algorithm inside the Ivy and we run it, we are going to execute this 24 times.
We have 24 statements telling us that the system that are print at AI and J.
A, for example, anything OK, any numbers.
So since we are executing this, we have analog and remember guys.
The trick here is that J equal to J times through which result in log.